minecraftskins.net 2019-01-21

# Privacy Policy | Minecraft Skins

#### Introduction

Welcome to ACTdesign (UK) Ltd’s privacy notice.

ACTdesign (UK) Ltd respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

This privacy notice is provided in a format so that you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.

  1. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE
  2. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU
  3. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?
  4. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
  5. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA
  6. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS
  7. DATA SECURITY
  8. DATA RETENTION
  9. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS
  10. GLOSSARY

### 1\. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE

#### Purpose of this privacy notice

This privacy notice applies to the information collected by ACTdesign (UK) Ltd, including through the following websites:

and through any interactive features, applications, widgets, blogs, social networks and other online or wireless offerings that post a link to this privacy notice, whether accessed via a computer, mobile device or other technology (collectively, “ACTdesign Websites”).

The ACTdesign Websites are not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected personal data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

#### Controller

ACTdesign (UK) Ltd is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice).

If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact us.

#### Contact details

Our full details are:

Full name of legal entity: ACTdesign (UK) Ltd, a private limited company with registered number 09182241

Postal address: C/O Womble Bond Dickinson (UK) LLP, St Ann's Wharf, 112 Quayside, Newcastle Upon Tyne NE1 3DX

To contact us, please use the “Contact Us” section of each ACTdesign Website. For any queries relating to [https://www.minecraft-crafting.net](https://www.minecraft-crafting.net/) or [http://www.minecraftcrafting.info](http://www.minecraftcrafting.info/), please use the contact page at <https://minecraftservers.org/contact> and provide sufficient information within your message to specify which ACTdesign Website your message relates to.

We hope that we can resolve any query or concern you raise about our use of your information. We would appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns in the first instance. However, you also have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)).

#### Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes

This version was last updated in November 2018 and historic versions can be obtained by contacting us.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

#### Third-party links

ACTdesign Websites may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave a ACTdesign Website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

### 2\. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

  * **Identity Data** includes first name, maiden name, last name, username (where this identifies an individual) or similar identifier.
  * **Contact Data** includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * **Transaction Data** includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access a ACTdesign Website.
  * **Profile Data** includes purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences and feedback.
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use a ACTdesign Website, or our products and services.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific ACTdesign Website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

We do not collect any financial data such as bank account or payment card details. Any payments that you make to us will be processed through third party service providers. See How is your data collected? for more information.

#### If you fail to provide personal data

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, where a server operator wishes to add their server to [https://minecraftservers.org](https://minecraftservers.org/)).

### 3\. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct Interactions.** You may give us your Identity and Contact Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by email or through one of our “Contact Us” sections on a ACTdesign Website. This includes personal data you provide when you: 
    * create an account on one of our ACTdesign Websites;
    * purchase advertising;
    * participate in an advertising bidding process;
    * submit enquiries;
    * give us some feedback.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with one of our ACTdesign Websites, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies.
  * **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below: 
    * Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU;
    * Contact and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such as Coinbase and Paypal based outside the EU;
    * Identity and Contact Data from publicly available sources such as Companies House and the Electoral Register based inside the EU.

### 4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.

We have set out below a description of the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

  * **Purpose/Activity:** To register you as a new user 
    * **Type of data:**  (a) Identity (b) Contact
    * **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest:**  Performance of a contract with you
  * **Purpose/Activity:** To manage our relationship with you which will include notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy 
    * **Type of data:** (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Marketing and Communications
    * **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest:** (a) Performance of a contract with you (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation (c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/ services)
  * **Purpose/Activity:** To administer and protect our business and any ACTdesign Website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) 
    * **Type of data:** (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Technical
    * **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest:** (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security and to prevent fraud) (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
  * **Purpose/Activity:** To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you 
    * **Type of data:** (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Usage (e) Marketing and Communications (f) Technical
    * **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest:** Necessary for our legitimate interests in placing advertisements that have an increased relevance to our customers
  * **Purpose/Activity:** To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences 
    * **Type of data:** (a) Technical (b) Usage
    * **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest:** Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)

#### Marketing

ACTdesign Websites do not send out any marketing messages. The only time you would receive an email from us is when registering through one of our ACTdesign Websites (to verify your address) if you have misplaced your password and need a reset link, or you have not complied with our Terms of Website Use or Website Acceptable Use Policy.

#### Google Adsense

Our ACTdesign Websites use Google’s Adsense technology which is a service from Google. AdSense provides a way for website owners to earn money from their online content.

AdSense works by matching text and display ads to our ACTdesign Websites based on our content and visitors. The ads are created and paid for by advertisers who want to promote their products.

We do not see your Google data. You can disable the AdSense feature by making the appropriate settings under [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/) and you can find additional information about the collection and use of data by Google under <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.

#### Cookies

ACTdesign Websites use cookies to distinguish you from other visitors to our ACTdesign Websites and to store information about visitor preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user accesses or visits, customise webpage content based on visitor browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when browsing our ACTdesign Websites and also allows us to improve their functionality.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

#### DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our ACTdesign Websites. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to our ACTdesign Websites and other sites on the Internet (including the use of Adsense).

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to display the advertisements and links that appear on our ACTdesign Websites and they automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalise the advertising content that you see. We have no access to, or control over, these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. This privacy notice does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our ACTdesign Websites may become inaccessible or not function properly.

#### Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

### 5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.

  * External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
  * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

### 6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

Our ACTdesign Websites use technology from external third parties based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission.
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between Europe and the US.

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

### 7\. DATA SECURITY

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

### 8\. DATA RETENTION

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see request erasure below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

### 9\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please see the glossary below to find out more about these rights:

  * Request access to your personal data
  * Request correction of your personal data
  * Request erasure of your personal data
  * Object to processing of your personal data
  * Request restriction of processing your personal data
  * Request transfer of your personal data
  * Right to withdraw consent

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

#### No fee usually required

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

#### What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

#### Time limit to respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

### 10\. GLOSSARY

####  LAWFUL BASIS

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

**Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

#### THIRD PARTIES

#### External Third Parties

We employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf such as:

  * Service providers acting as processors based inside and outside the EEA. These services may include fulfilling orders for advertising, providing customer relationship management, marketing assistance and supporting our website and IT functionality. These service providers may be supplied with or have access to your personal data solely for the purpose of providing these services to us on our behalf. ACTdesign (UK) Ltd is the data controller and will remain accountable for your personal data.
  * Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based inside the EEA who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
  * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.

#### YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS

You have the right to:

  * **Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  * **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
  * **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
  * **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
  * **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
  * **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

### ACTdesign (UK) Ltd
